Guide to the Chancellor of the University of Pittsburgh, David H. Kurtzman (Acting), Administrative Files, 1966-1967 UA.2.10.1966-1967
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Women's Education, Office of (Box 36, Folder 349)
  Caryl M. Kline
- W (General) (Box 36, Folder 350)
  Women, WQED, West Virginia University
- Y (General) (Box 36, Folder 351)
- State Related Status (Box 36, Folder 352-353)
- University Study Committee (Box 37, Folder 354)
  Final report, February 24, 1966; Committee; Progress reports; University Program concepts of the past decade, by Stanton C. Crawford, 1965; Minutes of the committee; Task Forces: No. 1 Educational goals, no. 2 Teaching effectiveness, No. 3 Financial support & Commonwealth relationship; Financial crisis, 1965 - -Analysis of the pertinent financial decisions leading up to the University's present non liquid condition. Some confidential memos on the matter. Pitt service to Commonwealth, 5/11/1965
- Ford Foundation Study Committee (Wells Report) (Box 37, Folder 355)
  Study Committee; Members; Herman B. Wells, Indiana University is Chairman; Reports on the Trimester; Reports on activities in connection with Federal Agencies, from John Geise, 1965; Financial survey analysis, 1955-65 (a background paper); Minutes
- Ford Foundation Study Committee (Wells Report) (Box 38, Folder 356)
  Report. Survey Committee; Chronology of events; A Selective review with proposals for future paths; a report by a special committee of the Ford Foundation
- Ad Hoc Committee to study the Wells Report (Box 38, Folder 357)
  Report to the faculty, senate, university administration, and Board of Trustees; Faculty recommendations concerning policies and actions Proposed by the Wells' Committee from the Graduate School of Public and International Affairs; Studies pursuant to Wells Report (outline of suggested studies): Organization of studies to follow through; Report of the Ad Hoc Faculty committee to evaluate the Wells Committee report
- State Relatedness (Box 38, Folder 358)
  Proposals and plans re state relatedness; Selective analysis of development programs at state-related universities by Richard D. Wagner; State relationship, problems re tuition; clippings on state relatedness
- State Board of Education Master Plan (Box 39, Folder 359-360)
  Master Plan Advisory Committee: Sidney Tickton's Plan, Preliminary Report of the Community College Study, submitted by Ralph R. Fields & Associates, Observations on some central issues relating to the Master Plan for Higher Education in Pennsylvania, 1966; Meetings of the Master Plan Advisory Committee: Summary of comments on the Report of Progress on a master plan, Minority report…, 1966, Report of progress on the master plan; Biographical data; Council of Higher Education
- Office Files (Box 40, Folder 361-366)
  FF 361 Letters to Council on Higher Education and Governor Scranton, re State Relationship
  FF 362 State appropriations Library and Information Sciences, School of; Medicine, School of; General maintenance; Salk (Western Psychiatric Institute); Penn State and Temple
  FF 363 Faculty letters and resolutions, re the future of the university. Also Seal of the University of Pittsburgh of the Commonwealth system of Higher Education.
  FF 364 Meetings of Heads of Colleges and University. (On budget) December 17, 1962; November 29, 1962; October 25, 1962
  FF 365 Budget, 1961-67
  FF 366 Budget Projections through 1962-63; Hearings, January 16, 1962
- Office Files (Box 41, Folder 367-373)
  FF 366 Budget; Projections through 1962-63; Hearings, January 16, 1962
- Office Files (Box 42, Folder 374-382)
  FF 374 Meetings of state-aided presidents, 1958/59
  FF 375 Meetings of State-Aided presidents, 1957/58
  FF 376 Progress report – Research Committee, April 30, 1958
  FF 377 Meetings of state-aided presidents, 1956/57
  FF 378 Meeting of state-aided presidents, February 12, 1958
  FF 379 Meetings of state-aided presidents, 1955/56
  FF 380 1957 Legislative follow-up letters
  FF 381 Legislative dinner, December 12, 1956
  FF 382 State appropriations 1955/57
- Office Files (Box 43, Folder 383-395)
  FF 383 Salaries Discussion, 1955
  FF 384 Slides A list, 1965
  FF 385 Instructions Policies
  FF 386 Trip to Quito, Ecuador, Mexico, etc., July, 1966
  FF 387 Parking Permits
  FF 388 Boards of Trustees and Committees 1964-1967
  FF 389 Fund raising expenses
  FF 390 University chauffeur
  FF 391 Dictaphones & typewriters (Chancellor's office)
  FF 392 Expense vouchers: Robert Bailie; Printing & duplicating
  FF 393 Expense vouchers: Office & instructional supplies; Purchased services and rentals; Telephone; Telegraph
  FF 394 Expense vouchers: Books & periodicals; Instructions re Purchasing; University membership dues, 1966
  FF 395 Expense vouchers: Travel, entertainment & related; Transportation requests; Football, 1966; Dr. Bailie; Special merchandise; Dr. Stanton C. Crawford, personal expenses
- Office Files (Box 44, Folder 396-405)
  FF 396 Expense vouchers, 1967: Travel, entertainment & related
  FF 397 Expense vouchers, 1967: Special merchandise
  FF 398 Expense vouchers: Dr. David H. Kurtzman
  FF 399 Special accounts 810-11-25
  FF 400 Discretionary funds – Receipts
  FF 401 Discretionary funds – Ecuador Project (Disbursements)
  FF 402 University membership dues, 1966
  FF 403 Chancellor's discretionary fund
  FF 404 Report by the University to the House and Senate Appropriations Committee and Task Force
  FF 405 Capital Budget, Proposed, 1967
- Office Files (Box 45, Folder 406-411)
  FF 406 Income and expense projections, 1967/68 – 1975/76 May 9, 1967
  FF 407 Capital program requests, 1967-73. State Planning Board v. 2, July 1966
  FF 408 Long range development plans as of 2/15/1961
  FF 409 Policy paper no. 1, edition no. 1, draft no. 2 January 15, 1958. Prepared by Chancellor Litchfield (confidential)
  FF 410 "A freedom budget" A. Philip Randolph Institute. July 1966. (confidential)
  FF 411 Financial Statements & Supplementary Information for fiscal year ending July 31, 1966; A financial survey and analysis, University of Pittsburgh 1955-65.